Guide to the Rice University James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy records, 1993-2014 UA 114
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series XVII: Digital archive of materials not represented physically
  - Subseries A: Documents and photographs
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 1995
      Foreign Policy Challenges at the End of the Century, November 13, 1995, reports and photographs, including Malcolm Gillis and Colin Powell. PDF copy of the Baker Institute Report, March, 1996.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 1996
      Program for Annual Conference, 1996.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 1997
      U.S. Foreign Policies on the Eve of the 21st Century, Oct. 16th, 1997 (includes photos of Djerejian, HW Bush, Kissinger and Gorbachev). Distinguished Lecture Series: Feb. 7, 1995 - Madeline Albright (photos) Distinguished Lecture Series: May 5, 1995 - Yasser Arafat (photos, also George HW and Barbara Bush, James A. Baker) Ernst and Young Energy Series: April 10, 1995 - Shiek Ahmed Zaki Yamani (photos) Baker 3rd Annual Conference: Oct. 15, 1997 - Photos of Kissinger and Gorbachev November 20, 1997 - Nursultan Nazarbayev (photos)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 1998
      Photos of Ambassador Djerejian and Lea Rabin. Photo of Djerejian from the Meltdown in East Asia lecture, October 23rd, 1998. Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: April 23rd, 1998 - Kofi Annan (Photos of Annan with Malcolm Gillis and Djerejian). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: October 23rd, 1998 - Lee Kuan Yew (Photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 1999
      CIIS Beijing Photos. Literature, Poetry and Public Policy photo, Feb. 10, 1999. Breakfast Address by Giscard d'Estaing, Feb. 25th, 1999 (photos of Valery Giscard d'Estaing and Malcolm Gilles and Djerejian). Round Table Meeting photos, March, 1999. U.S. Foreign Policy in Africa-Which Way Forward?, April 27, 1999 (photos of African delagation). China's Views on an Independent Taiwan, Sept. 17, 1999 (Tang Shubei photo). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Bob Lanier - April 28, 1999 (photo). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Andres Pastrana Arango - October 20, 1999 (Photos of Arango with James A. Baker and Ambassador Derejian). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Nelson Mandela - October 26, 1999 (Photos of Mandela with crowd and various dignitaries).
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2000
      Running on Empty-Prospecte for Future Oil Supply, May 19, 2000 (Thomas Ahlbrandt photo).
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2001
      The Geography Behind Geopolitics, March 6, 2001 (Photo James A. Baker). Forum on the Role of the National Security Advisor, April 12, 2001 (Photos). The Role of the Secretary of the Treasury, October 5, 2001 (Photo). With God On Their Side-The Impact of Islamic, Jewish, and Christian Fundamentalism, October 30, 2001 (Photo). State Infrastructure Protection Advisory Committee Meeting, December 17, 2001 (Photo with John Cornyn and Michael McCaul). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Alberto R. Gonzales, Sept. 7, 2001 (Photo). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Al Faisal Al Sa'ud, Sept. 21, 2001 (Photo). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Abdelaziz Bouteflika, Nov. 2, 2001 (Photo). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Alan Greenspan, Nov. 13, 2001 (Photos). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Vladimir Putin, Nov. 14, 2001 (Photos of Putin and George HW Bush). Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Nambaryn Enkhbayar, Nov. 19, 2001 (Photo). The Future of the Oil Industry (Alan Greenspan photo).
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2002
      U.S.-Syrian Dialogue - May 20, 2002 (Photos). The Future of the Space Program and Space Policy - August 26, 2002 (Photo) U.S.-Russia Commercial Energy Summit - October 2, 2002 (Photo) Conference on U.S. Drug Policy - 2002 (Photo of Chief Lee Brown, HPD) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Vaira Vike-Freiberga - Feb. 7, 2002 (Photo of Vike-Freiberga and Djerejian) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: King Abdullah - May 9, 2002 (Photos of King Abdullah with James A. Baler and Edward Djerejian)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2003
      Afghanistan Symposium - February, 2003 (Zalmay Khalilzad and Derejian photo) Qian Qichen - November 6, 2003 (Photos) The Various Confrontations in Isreal Today - November 7, 2003 (Amos Oz and Djerejian photos) Address by Dr. Amartya Sen - Novemvber 11, 2003 (Photo Dr. Sen and Djerejian) Middle East Conflicts and Nuclear Proliferation - November 18, 2003 (Photo) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Helmut Kohl - October 1, 2003 (Kohl and James A. Baker at Berlin Wall photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Olusegun Obasanjo - November 5, 2003 (Photos)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2004
      Changing Minds, Winning Peace - January 20, 2004 (Photo) Raymond Dubois - February 13, 2004 (Photo) Moshe Ma'oz - February 17, 2004 (Photos) Clark Randt Student Forum Coffee - February 26, 2004 (Photo) Working Together in the Post-911 World - April 22, 2004 (Anders Fogh Rasmussen and Djerejian photos) The Gropolitics of Natural Gas: From Today to 2030 - May 26, 2004 (Photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Hosni Mubarak - April 14, 2004 (Mubarak, Djerejian and Baker photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Sheikh Hamad Bin Khalifa Al Thani - September 28, 2004 (Photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Rudolph W. Giuliani - September 29, 2004 (Giuliani, Djerejian and Baker photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Tom Brokaw - November 15, 2004 (Photos)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2005
      Israeli-Palestinian Workshop - 2005 (Photos) U.S.-Arab Relations: Outlook For 2005 - January 31, 2005 (Amr Moussa and James A. Baker photos) U.S.-Japan Joint Seminar - July 20, 2005 (Photo) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Prince Saud Al Faisal - September 21, 2005 (Photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2006
      American Vertigo - February 13, 2006 (Photo) Robert Mosbacher - April 12, 2006 (Photo) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Shimon Peres - January 16, 2006 (Photos) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Shri Murli Deora - March 31, 2006 (Photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2007
      The Woman's Issue - May 20, 2007 (Photo) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Bill Clinton - August 2, 2007 (Lecture pamphlet and photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2009
      Policy Lunch with Fellow Bill Martin - March 23, 2009 (Photos) America and China: The Next Thirty Years - April 3, 2009 (Henry Kissinger and James A. Baker photo) Ambassadresses at Large - April 21, 2009 (PDF document and PDF intro remarks by Francoise Djerejian)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2011
      Twenty Years After Madrid - November 2, 2011 (Djerejian and George H.W. Bush photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Conferences and Summits, 2016
      American Leadership in a Changing International Landscape - February 24, 2016 ( Warren Christopher, Kissinger, Bernard Shaw, etc. photo)
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2003
      Baker Institute 10th Anniversary Gala. Photos of James A. Baker, Ambassador Djerejian, Malocolm Gillis, etc. and their spouses.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2005
      Baker 75th Birthday, April 28th, 2005. Photos of James A. Baker's 75th birthday, includes George H.W. Bush, Barbara Bush, Prof. William Martin and his wife Patricia, and Rice Pres. David Leebron.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2008
      Baker Institute 15th Anniversary. Includes PDF of a newspaper article about the Baker Institute's 15th anniversary.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2013
      20th Anniversary Gala, November 8th, 2013. Includes PDFs of the gala program, the dinner menu and assorted ephemera (including invitations, donation forms, etc.) and photos of attendees such as Malcolm Gillis, Ambassador Djerejian and James A. Baker.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2015
      Layalina Awards Gala, March 18, 2015 (Washington D.C.). Includes PDF of Gala program and PDF of Awards Presentation program.
    - Major events at Baker Institute: Galas, 2018
      Baker 25th Anniversary, Nov. 27th, 2018. Includes PDF of the event program and photos of James A. Baker, Barack Obama and Ambassador Djerejian.
    - Origination: 1994 opening records
      Articles about goundbreaking of Baker Institute (PDF's include Rice University press release, Houston Post article, and article about former US presidents speaking at event). Letters (Includes PDF's of letters to various dignataries such as Bill CLinton, Warren Christopher, and Yitzhak Rabin regarding Djerejian's retirement as ambassador and appointment as head of the Baker Institute). Memo (PDF of a telegram from Bill Clinton to Djerejian accepting resignation). Miscellaneous (Includes PDF's of Edward Djerejian's CV, Francoise Djerejian's CV, and a Rice University map). Schedules (Includes PDF's of Ambassador Djerejian's schedule for May 19-21 and May 25, 1994). Speeche (PDF of speech from May 20, 1994 at Rice University).
    - Baker Institute background information
      PDF's of informational pamphlets regarding the Baker Institute.
    - Building Construction, n.d.
      Houston Chronicle article from October 14, 1997 about the new James A. Baker Hall. Photos of newly constructed Baker Institute building. PDF of building layout images.
    - Building Dedication, 1997-10-15
      Photos of Baker Institute building dedication and dinner.
    - Groundbreaking, 1994-10-20
      Articles (Articles about the groundbreaking and dedication of the Baker INstitute). Budget (PDF of groundbreaking events working budget). Donor Video (PDF of donor video production estimate). George Bush (PDF's of George H.W. Bush's biography, letters between H.W. Bush and James A. Baker, PDF of H.W. Bush's schedule, and PDF's of H.W. Bush's speech). Gerald Ford (PDF's of Ford's biography, schedule and speech plus photos). Jimmy Carter (PDF's of Carter's speech, newspaper articles and video budgets). Miscellaneous (Includes PDF's of Rice President Malcolm Gillis's biography, groundbreaking ceremony schedule, seating plan, etc.). Photos of groundbreaking ceremony (includes former U.S. Presidents Gerald Ford and George H.W. Bush woth Baker and Djerejian). Press Releases (PDF's of press releases surroundinhg the groundbreaking of the Baker Institute). Reception (PDF's of groundbreaking ceremony reception menu and buffet layout). Ronald Reagan (PDF's of Reagan's biography, correspondence with Gillis and Baker, groundbreaking ceremony speech and video production estimate). Timelines (PDF's of groundbreaking ceremony planning timelines).
    - Interviews, n.d.
      Ambassador Djerejian (Audio and video files of interview with Djerejian-includes transcript). Bill Barnett (Audio file and transcript of interview with Bill Barnett). John Rogers (Audio and video files of interview with John Rogers-includes transcript). Rick Stoll (Audio and video files of interview with Rick Stoll-includes transcript). James A. Bakes III (Audio file and transcript of interview with Baker).
    - Leadership Committee, 1993-1994
      Correspondence (PDF's of correspondence between James A. Baker and various individuals). Leadership Committee Meeting 1993 (PDF's of LCM handbook, LCM documents, and LCM summary). Leadership Committee Meeting 1994 (Images of assigned prospects, contacts, floor plans, agendas, committee names, status reports for campaigns and finances, and unassigned prospects).
  - Subseries B: Videos of Baker Institute events
    - Video: Baker Institute ground breaking ceremonies and Palestinian-Isreali conflict lecture, 1994-10-20-2020-05-09; 1.67 Gigabytes
      This object contains two (2) videos 1) Baker Institute ground breaking ceremonies, Oct 20, 1994. 2) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: The Palestinian-Isreali Conflict, May 9, 2020.
    - Video: US foreign policy lecture and the Middle East and Israel lecture, 1997-10-16-2006-01-16; 1.84 Gigabytes
      Object contains two (2) videos 1) US Foreign Policy Priorities on the Eve of the 21st Century lecture, Oct. 16, 1997 2) Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: The Middle East and Israel, Jan. 16, 2006
    - Nelson Mandela lecture, 1999-10-26; 1.08 Gigabytes
      Video footage Shell Distinguished Lecture Series: Nelson Mandela, Former President of South Africa and Nobel Peace Prize Winner, Oct. 26, 1999
- Series XVIII: Richard J. Stoll
  - Eisenhower Institute Grant Proposal, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Quandt Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - FYO: from E. Djerejian by Date, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Mexico: General, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Memorandums and Quotes, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Baker Institute Research Agenda, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Working Conference M.D. Anderson, 1994-1996 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Building, 1 of 2, 1994-1996 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Building, 2 of 2, 1994-1996 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - EPD Talk Notes, 1994-1997 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - BIPP Concerns, 1994-1998 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Tamari Foundation, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Tex-Mex Attorney General Conference-G. Marshall, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - United Nations Speaker, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Doctor Brown Appointment, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Asia Conference, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report Discussion, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Brice Contributions, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Energy and Environment Systems Institute, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Building: Electronic Stuff, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Anthropology Initiatives, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Center for the Study of Drugs and Society Enterprise, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Potential Cooperative Institutes, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Mosher Institute, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Health Care, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Joint Projects, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Middle East Research Agenda, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Middle East Research (Tamari), 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Lockheimer and Ota, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Baker Institute Naming Opportunities, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Transcultural, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Appointment Process, 1 of 2, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Appointment Process, 2 of 2, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - General Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Prospects, 1995-1998 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Items to Discuss with E. Djerejian, 1995-1999 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Tax Reform, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - United Nations Reform Seminar May 22, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - PBS Documentary, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Syria, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Brochure Discussion, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Competitiveness Study Proposal, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Center for Study of Institutions and Values, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Ernst and Young Oil Seminar, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Loose Nukes Working Group, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Loose Nukes Harvard, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Israeli-Syrian Working Group, 1 of 2, 1996-1998 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Israeli-Syrian Working Group, 2 of 2, 1996-1998 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - The Americas Project, 1 of 2, 1996-2000 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - The Americas Project, 2 of 2, 1996-2000 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Urban Study (Stein), 1997 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - West University: International City/County Management Association, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Western Sahara, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Department Fund Budget Status for Fiscal Years 1997 and 1998 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - American Assembly, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Athletics Committee, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Board of Advisors Proposal, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Potential Fellows and Visitors, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Intel, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Research Advisory Committee, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Sid Richardson Foundation, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Rice Department Chairs and Administrative Officials, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Senior Health Policy Fellow Search, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Anticipated Events, 1997-2000 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - A Public Policy Framework for Social and Health Inequalities, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Symposium on Public Science Policy, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Dedication of the Isaac and Mildred Brochstein Fellow in Peace and Security in Honor of Yitzhak Rubin, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Richardson Senior Fellow in Health Policy, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Center for the Study of Cultures Proposals, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - EPD Talk Notes, 1998-2000 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement Conference: Access Mexico 99, Five Years of NAFTA Past and Future, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Globalization and Eroding Border Control: Developing a New US-Caribbean Regime to Meet the Challenge, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Baker Institute Operating and Related Costs, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Jones School, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Nelson Mandela Address Event Invitation Lists and Ancillary Documents, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Perspectives on U.S. Foreign Policy Issues October 25, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Dean and Vice President Invitations to Prince El Hassan Bin Talal of Jordan Presentation, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Ernst and Young CEO Seminar Proposal, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - The Overseas Development Council, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - North Korea Workshop II, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - International Professional Exchange Proposals, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - T. Sullivan Appointment and Related Materials, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Energy Forum, 1999-2001 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - City of Houston: Counter Terrorism Summer 99, 1999-2001 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Memory of Violence and Violence of Memory in the Middle East and North Africa Conference Funding Request, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Job Inquiries, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Drugs, Thugs, and Trade: Border Control in an Era of Hemispheric Economic Integration, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Michigan State University Meeting, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Ramos Foundation, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Religion and Public Policy Reflections on Elections Series, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Texas Foundation for Society and Health, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Latin American Energy Studies Program, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Work Appointment Materials, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Transitional China Project Funding, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Pending Proposals and Research Ideas, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Wallace Wilson Research Fellow Search, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Space Congress 2002, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Space Policy Summit Planning Meeting, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Common Ground Initiative, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Subseries A: Annual Conference
    - Annual Conference, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Annual Conference, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Annual Conference, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Center for International Political Economy
    - Center for International Political Economy (CIPE)-Middle East, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - CIPE Faculty and Proposals, 1995-1996 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - CIPE Meeting May 16, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - CIPE Final Report, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - CIPE 2, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - CIPE 3, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - CIPE 4, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - CIPE 5, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Series XIX: Latin American Initiatives
  - International Visitor Leadership Program, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Americas Project, 1996-1998 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Trade and Reform: The Political, Economic, and Social Implications of Free Trade in America Photographs, 1 of 3, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Trade and Reform: The Political, Economic, and Social Implications of Free Trade in America Photographs, 2 of 3, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Trade and Reform: The Political, Economic, and Social Implications of Free Trade in America Photographs, 3 of 3, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Americas Project Event Programs, 1998-2003 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Americas Project, 2000-2002 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Americas Project, 1 of 5, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Americas Project, 2 of 5, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Americas Project, 3 of 5, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Americas Project, 4 of 5, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Americas Project, 5 of 5, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Americas Project Financials, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Interoffice Memorandums, Communications, and Drafts, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - R. Duch Survey, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Americas Project, 1 of 4, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Americas Project, 2 of 4, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Americas Project, 3 of 4, 2003 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Americas Project, 4 of 4, 2003 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Americas Project, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Americas Project, 2006-2007 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Americas Project, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Papers prepared for U.S.-Mexico Border Program, 2008-2009 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Americas Project, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - World Affairs Council of Houston, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Energy Event Mexico February 3-4, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - The Mexico-U.S. Border Through the Lens of a Screenwriter November 12, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Energy, Policy and Politics: The Changing Energy Landscape in Latin America February 26, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Drug Violence at the U.S.-Mexico Border: Lessons Learned after 40 years of the U.S.' War on Drugs, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Meetings from Honduras, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Ambassador Gallegos of Ecuador Visit October 23, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Organization of American States Revised Agreement, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Border Economies Research, 2009-2010 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Americas Project 2010: Colloquium (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Development Strategies for Baker Institute Latin American Initiative (BILAI), 2010 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Freedom to Report: Journalism and Politics in Latin America April 29, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Americas Project, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 21)
- Series XX: James A. Baker III
  - Meeting Global Challenges: American Leadership in the Post-Cold War Era Lecture, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Woodson Research Center (WRC) former James A. III Baker (JAB) Public Service Archive, 1 of 4, 1993-2004 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - WRC former JAB III Public Service Archive, 2 of 4, 1993-2004 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - WRC former JAB III Public Service Archive, 3 of 4, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - WRC former JAB III Public Service Archive, 4 of 4, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Leadership Committee General Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Selective Engagement: Principles for American Foreign Policy In a New Era Lecture, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - BIPP Groundbreaking Ceremony, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Groundbreaking October 20, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Groundbreaking Press Releases October 20, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Access Correspondence for James A. Baker III Papers, 1957-2011 at Princeton, 1 of 3, 1994-2006 (Box 33, Folder 7)